[{"question":"Which of the following is the largest lymphatic vessels of the human body?","a":"Lacteal duct ","b":"Thoracic Duct","c":"Cisterna Chyli","d":"Right Lymphatic Duct","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following cations is required for the conversion of prothrombin into active thrombin by thromboplastin?","a":"Cu2+","b":"Fe3+","c":"Fe2+","d":"Ca2+","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"The normal pH of the arterial blood is:","a":"6.8 ","b":"7.8","c":"7.4 ","d":"8.8","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"If cardiac supply of vagus nerve is cut then:","a":"Rate of heart beat increases.","b":"Rate of heart beat decreases.","c":"There is no change in heart beat.","d":"Heart stops beating.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Blood pressure increases and heart rate decreases in response to:","a":"Exercise","b":"Haemorrage","c":"Exposure to high altitude","d":"Increased intracranial pressure","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Systolic pressure of heart is higher than diastolic pressure, because","a":"blood is forcefully pumped into arteries by the heart during systole and not during diastole.","b":"arteries offer resistance to the flowing of blood during systole only.","c":"arteries contract during systole only.","d":"volume of blood in heart is greater during systole than during diastole.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Anaemia due to failure of maturation of BC is:","a":"Von Kluger's disease","b":"Microcytic anaemia","c":"Normocytic anaemia","d":"Pernicious anaemia","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which of the following accelerates extrinsic or tissue thromboplastin formation?","a":"Factor VII (proconvertin)","b":"Factor XI (plasma thromboplastin antecedent)","c":"Heparin","d":"Calcium","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following structures of the lymphatic system acts primarily as a filter for detecting and destroying microorganisms in lymph traveling through major lymph vessels?","a":"Lymph nodes Thinking ","b":"Thymus","c":"Lymph Capillaries","d":"Tonsil, But Not The Appendix","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"pH of blood in arteries and veins is:","a":"Same ","b":"More in arteries and less in veins","c":"More in veins and less in arteries ","d":"None Of the above ","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The blood protein involved in blood coagulation is:","a":"Heparin ","b":"Prothrombin","c":"Thrombin","d":"All Of These","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"An open circulatory system occurs in:","a":"Reptiles ","b":"Man","c":"Animals","d":"Insects","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"In the ABO system of blood groups, if both antigens are present but no antibody, the blood group of the individual would be:","a":"B","b":"O","c":"AB","d":"A","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following organs can be called as a sort of \"blood bank\"?","a":"Lungs ","b":"Heart","c":"Liver","d":"Spleen","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Hematocrit value is the expression of:","a":"ratio of oxyhemoglobin and reduced haemoglobin in blood.","b":"ratio of normal and abnormal haemoglobin in blood.","c":"ratio of red blood corpuscles to plasma in blood.","d":"None of the above.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which one of the following blood vessel is without valves?","a":"Artery","b":"Vein","c":"Pulmonary Aorta","d":"Systemic Aorta","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"A vein possesses a large lumen because:","a":"tunica media and tunica externa form a single coat.","b":"tunica media and tunica interna form a single coat.","c":"tunica interna, tunica media and tunica externa are thin.","d":"tunica media is a thin coat.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"The purpose of the AV node is to____ and the purpose of the Purkinie fibres is to___.","a":"create simultaneous atrial and ventricular depolarisation; speed up transmission of the cardiac impulse into the ventricle.","b":"delay ventricular depolarisation relative to atrial depolarisation; insulate the cardiac","c":"delay ventricular depolarisation relative to atrial depolarisation; transmit the cardiac impulse to very small localised groups of ventricular fibres.","d":"delay atrial depolarisation relative to ventricular depolarisation; transmit the cardiac impulse to very small localised groups of ventricular fibres.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"If cardiac output is 6.0 L/min and 1.44 L of urine is formed daily, what percentage of flow in the nephrons and collecting ducts is reabsorbed (kidneys receive 20% of cardiac output)?","a":"0.1% ","b":"0.02%","c":"99.9% ","d":"Data Insufficient","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"The pacemaker of the human heart is:","a":" SA Node ","b":"Tricuspid Valve","c":" AV Node","d":"All Of These","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Papillary muscles are associated with:","a":"Ventricles","b":"Auricles","c":"Dorsal Aorta","d":"Sinus Venosus","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"If nerves of heart are cut, then heart will:","a":"Beat rhythmically ","b":"Stop Working","c":"Beat arhythmically ","d":"Shrink","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Cardiac output is:","a":"the product of heart rate and stroke volume.","b":"the product of auricular and ventricular volume.","c":"the blood pumped in one minute.","d":"Both (a) and (c)","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"In the human body, the highest blood pressure can be recorded in:","a":"arteries near the heart. ","b":"Veins Returning To The Heart.","c":"apillaries Of The Body Tissue","d":"The Lungs","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Carotid artery carries:","a":"impure blood from the brain.","b":"impure blood to kidneys.","c":"oxygenated blood to the brain.","d":"oxygenated blood to the heart.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Pulmonary aorta in mammalian embryo communicates with carotico-systemic aorta by a thin vessel called ductus arteriosus which later closes and remains in adult as:","a":"Fossa ovalis","b":"Ligamentum Arteriosus","c":"Carotico-pulmonary aperture","d":"None Of The Above","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The heart sound 'murmur' is heard during:","a":"closing of bicuspid and tricuspid valves.","b":"Closing Of Semiluner Valves.","c":"leaking of blood through valves.","d":"All Of The Above","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Myocardial Infarction is caused by:","a":"hardening of arteries.","b":"lumpy thickness develop in the inner walls of arteries.","c":"clot which may occur in the lumen of a coronary artery.","d":"sudden interruption in blood flow towards a portion of heart.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"In arteriosclerosis:","a":"arterial walls become very thin and weak so that the blood oozes out of the walls.","b":"sex linked heredity is involved.","c":"blood coagulates even in the arteries.","d":"arterial walls become inelastic and thickened.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which layer of the wall of blood vessels is made up of circular smooth muscles?","a":"Outer ","b":"Middle","c":"Inner","d":"Both (A) And (B)","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"First heart sound (Lubb) coincides with the____wave of ECG:","a":"R","b":"T","c":"P","d":"Q","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"QRST is related with:","a":"Ventricular contraction or depolarisation","b":"Auricular contraction","c":"Auricular relaxation","d":"Cardiac cycle","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Child death may occur in the marriage between:","a":"Rh+ man and Rh+ woman.","b":"Rh+ man and Rh- woman.","c":"Rh+man and Rh- woman.","d":"Rh- man and Rh+ woman.","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Artery differs from vein in having:","a":"Narrow wall ","b":"Thick Walls","c":"Valves","d":"None Of The Above","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"\"P' wave of ECG occurs before the:","a":"onset of ventricular contraction.","b":"end of arterial contraction.","c":"beginning of atrial contraction.","d":"None of the above.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":" In human, the opening of post caval in the right auricle is guarded by:","a":"Bicuspid valve ","b":"Tricuspid Valve","c":"Eustachian valve ","d":"Sino-Auricular Valve","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Wall of blood capillary is formed of:","a":"Haemocytes ","b":"Parietal Cells","c":"Endothelial Cells","d":"Oxyntic Cells","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Heart beats are accelerated by:","a":"Cranial nerves and acetylcholine","b":"Sympathetic nerves and acetylcholine","c":"Cranial nerves and adrenaline","d":"Sympathetic nerves and epinephrine","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Inmammals, veins differs from arteries in having:","a":"Thicker walls ","b":"Deeply Present","c":"Carry Blood Away From Heart","d":"Internal Valves","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Which of the following best describes an artery?","a":"Carries blood away from the heart.","b":"Carries oxygenated blood.","c":"Contains valves.","d":"Has thin walls.","hint":"","correct":"a"}]